Hi, I'm Amelia.
And I'm going to show you how to scrunch your hair.
The technique with scrunching hair is really all about your hands.
You really want to use your hands to kind of get in there and lift that hair.
Step one, you want to make sure your hair is slightly damp it does not need to be soaking wet.
Just slightly damp.
So when you get out of the shower you just want to take your towel and kind of go in and just remove as much water as possible.
So that way your styling product doesn't get diluted.
Then you want to use some sort of balm, cream or mousse in your hair.
You can even use a spray gel.
So I like something that's got a little bit of hold to it.
So you just spray the hair with it and then take your hands and just scrunch it.
Now this is where you can use a dryer, or you don't have to, you can just leave the house like this with it slightly damp.
The more you scrunch it, the more body you'll get in your hair.
But it's all about taking, getting that hair into the palm of your hand.
You want to grab that hair, and squish it and push it up towards the scalp.
So grab it and push it up towards the scalp.
And that is creating the bend.
So that in turn gets you that nice beachy wave look.
And that's how you scrunch your hair.